portlandtribune.com 2019-12-14

# Pamplin Media Group - Pamplin Media Group

This Privacy Policy ('Policy') applies to all of the products, services and web sites offered by the Pamplin Media Group newspapers. 

* * *

**_Information we collect and how we use it:_**

In order to provide our full range of services, we may collect the following types of information: 

Information you provide - When you sign up for a service or promotion that requires registration, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address and an account password). For certain services we also request credit card or other payment account information which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers. 

Cookies - When you visit one of our web sites, we send one or more cookies - a small file containing a string of characters - to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled. 

Log information - Our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a web site. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 

Affiliated sites - We offer some of our services in connection with other web sites. Personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to the Pamplin Media Group in order to deliver the service. We process such information in accordance with this Policy. The affiliated sites may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies. 

Other sites - This Policy applies to web sites and services that are owned and operated by the Pamplin Media Group. 

The Pamplin Media Group only processes personal information for the purposes described in the applicable Policy and/or privacy notice for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include: 

Providing our products and services to users, including the display of customized content and advertising; 

Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services; 

Ensuring the technical functioning of our network; and 

Developing new services. 

You can find more information about how we process personal information by referring to the privacy notices for particular services. 

**_Choices for personal information_**

When you sign up for a particular service that requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different than the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use. 

If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Policy and/or in the specific service notices, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Policy and/or in the specific service notices, unless we have obtained your prior written consent. 

You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case we may not be able to provide those services to you. 

**_Information sharing_**

The Pamplin Media Group only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of the Pamplin Media Group in the following limited circumstances: 

We have your written consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information. 

We provide such information to our parent company or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. 

We have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable terms of service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of the Pamplin Media Group, its users or the public as required or permitted by law. 

If the Pamplin Media Group becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-personal information, such as the number of users who searched for a particular story, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular advertisement. Such information does not identify you individually. 

Please contact us at the address below for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data. 

**_Information security_**

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. 

We restrict access to personal information to Pamplin Media Group employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. 

**_Data integrity_**

The Pamplin Media Group processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary. 

**_Accessing and updating personal information_**

When you use our services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Some of our services have different procedures to access, correct or delete users' personal information. 

**_Enforcement_**

The Pamplin Media Group regularly reviews its compliance with this Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy or our treatment of personal information by contacting us through this web site or by writing to us at Privacy Matters, Attn: Webmaster, The Pamplin Media Group, 6605 SE Lake Road, Portland OR 97222, USA. When we receive formal written complaints at this address, it is our policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between the Pamplin Media Group and an individual. 

**_Changes to this policy_**

Please note that this Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Policy without your explicit written consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Policy changes). Each version of this Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date, and we will also keep prior versions of this Policy in an archive for your review. 

**_Comment Policy_**

Comments are welcomed and encouraged on this site, but there are some instances where comments will be edited or deleted as follows: 

\- Comments deemed to be spam or solely promotional in nature will be deleted. Links to external content is permitted, but comments should be relevant to the post topic and would have to be moderated. 

\- Comments including profanity will be deleted. 

\- Comments containing language or concepts that could be deemed offensive will be deleted. Note this may include abusive, threatening, pornographic, offensive, misleading or libelous language. 

\- Comments that attack an individual directly will be deleted. 

\- Comments that harass other posters will be deleted. Please be respectful toward other contributors. 

The owner of this news site reserves the right to edit or delete any comments submitted to the blog without notice. This comment policy is subject to change at any time. 

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Policy, please feel free to contact us any time through this web site or at Pamplin Media Group Attn: Webmaster, 6605 SE Lake Road, Portland, OR 97222, USA.
